<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Alex Clark - Python Web Developer</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.aclark.net/feeds/Django.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.aclark.net/</id><updated>2013-01-31T13:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Please Help Me Do Open Source Work</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net//2013/01/31/please-help-me-do-open-source-work/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-31T13:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>aclark</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2013-01-31:/2013/01/31/please-help-me-do-open-source-work/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From my 'mid-life-crisis' series of blog entries :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://raw.github.com/ACLARKNET/aclarknet.github.com/master/images/open-source-work.png" src="https://raw.github.com/ACLARKNET/aclarknet.github.com/master/images/open-source-work.png" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Source Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source Work&lt;/strong&gt; has paid my bills for a long time. Starting with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://plone.org"&gt;Plone&lt;/a&gt; in the early 2000s, to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; in the early 2010s, to now. And for this, I am very grateful. To be clear: it's not exactly the &lt;em&gt;Open Source Work&lt;/em&gt; that has paid my bills, it's the consulting work I've been able to secure as a result of my dedication and devotion to open source software and communities. Which is great! (Even more clear: my dedication and devotion to open source software and communities has made learning new skills fun. And those skills have paid my bills for the past 8 years.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Open Source Work is awesome. I'll likely spend my entire life doing it (in some capacity or another). And while Open Source Work does not pay, the experience is invaluable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saas-offering"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SaaS Offering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I caught the &amp;quot;startup bug&amp;quot; and have been interested in building a SaaS offering that would at least pay my bills, if not make me fantastically wealthy. Enter 2012's: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pythonpackages.com"&gt;pythonpackages.com&lt;/a&gt;. The year I spent doing pythonpackages.com work was awesome. I learned a lot. Traveled. Met a lot of cool folks who seemed genuinely interested in my idea(s). But unfortunately, I never made a dime doing it. The lesson, among others, is that &lt;strong&gt;SaaS offerings are hard&lt;/strong&gt;. I am now semi-focused on a &amp;quot;reboot&amp;quot; of the pythonpackages.com idea(s), but that's going to take a while to get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Consulting *was* the dream. Now building a SaaS offering *is* the dream (among others). So where does Open Source Work fit in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="play-as-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Play as Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been &amp;quot;working for a living&amp;quot; since age 14. Back then, I was a busboy and dishwasher in my family's Italian restaurant, where I first learned to &lt;strong&gt;work hard and have fun doing it&lt;/strong&gt;. Since then, I've always worked hard, had fun, and taken few vacations (except for 1994-1998 when I was a full time CS student). I suspect I will always &amp;quot;work for a living&amp;quot; though as I get older, the line between work and play becomes even blurrier. Everyone wants to love or at least like their work. But very few are able to turn their play in to paid work. I am very fortunate, I think, to know what I want to do in life. I know middle aged folk that still don't know the answer to these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: liking my work *was* the dream. Now turning the things I like to do into paid work *is* the dream. In 2013, I would like to spend more time doing Open Source Work, working on projects like&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/buildout"&gt;Buildout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dcpython.org"&gt;DC Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/python-imaging"&gt;Pillow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://plone.org"&gt;Plone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/codekoala/django-axes"&gt;django-axes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://resume.aclark.net/projects/#collective"&gt;et al&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;If you have benefited from my work on any of these projects, directly or indirectly, please consider making a&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gittip.com/aclark4life"&gt;gittip donation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to help me do more Open Source Work in 2013.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script data-gittip-username="aclark4life"
src="https://www.gittip.com/assets/widgets/0002.js"&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Django"></category><category term="Mozilla"></category><category term="Plone"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Python 3 Porting</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net//2013/01/10/python-3-porting/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-10T19:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>aclark</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2013-01-10:/2013/01/10/python-3-porting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 3 in 2013 is for Python 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://raw.github.com/ACLARKNET/aclarknet.github.com/master/images/python-3-port.jpg" src="https://raw.github.com/ACLARKNET/aclarknet.github.com/master/images/python-3-port.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to like projects that everyone else &lt;strong&gt;hates&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing persistent Python objects associated with missing classes in ZODB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making new releases for old software that is still useful but unmaintained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running flake8 on 10s or 100s of source files and hand-fixing the results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of this has to do with &lt;strong&gt;repetition&lt;/strong&gt;. I know how to do these things, and I like doing them. Over and over. If someone says, &amp;quot;my Data.fs file is broken&amp;quot; I get excited. Anyway, I hope you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-am-your-man"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I am your man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the subject of this post: &lt;strong&gt;Python 3 Porting&lt;/strong&gt;. I've been helping out porting the Python Imaging Library to Python 3 (via the Pillow fork, where I am the release manager). And it strikes me as the type of thing I'd be very interested in doing professionally. So, if you or your company are in need of a &amp;quot;workhorse&amp;quot; to plow through old code and update it, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aclark.net/team/alex-clark"&gt;I am your man&lt;/a&gt;. Please do &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;aclark.net"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-s-in-it-for-you"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's in it for you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I know what you are thinking: &lt;strong&gt;porting Python 2 software to Python 3 is a lot of work for little gain&lt;/strong&gt;. Maybe. Maybe not. I'm not going to try to convince you otherwise, however I will tell you this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For me, 2013 is &amp;quot;the year of Python 3&amp;quot;. I've now promised to deliver and maintain a &lt;strong&gt;Python 3 compatible PIL by PyCon 2013&lt;/strong&gt;. I now care about Python 3 (this was not true before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Python 3 Wall of Shame is now the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://python3wos.appspot.com/"&gt;Python 3 Wall of Superpowers&lt;/a&gt;. We are over the hump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many popular Python web frameworks support or are about to support Python 3 e.g. CherryPy, Django, Pyramid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there is no time like the present to &lt;strong&gt;take a serious look at Python 3&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Django"></category><category term="Mozilla"></category><category term="Plone"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>New Year's Python Meme 2012</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net//2012/12/29/new-years-python-meme-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-29T15:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>aclark</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2012-12-29:/2012/12/29/new-years-python-meme-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="https://raw.github.com/ACLARKNET/aclarknet.github.com/master/images/tarek-meme-reminder.png" src="https://raw.github.com/ACLARKNET/aclarknet.github.com/master/images/tarek-meme-reminder.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is my entry for Tarek Ziadé's New Year's Python Meme, a tradition I have come to enjoy. Both to reflect on the current year and look back on previous years. So here it is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.aclark.net/2009/12/31/new-years-python-meme/"&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.aclark.net/2011/12/21/new-years-python-meme-2011/"&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;. Let's try it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What’s the coolest Python application, framework or library you have discovered in 2012?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would be &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.python-requests.org/en/latest/"&gt;Kenneth Reitz's Requests&lt;/a&gt;. Like many others, I've been bitten by the elegance and simplicity bug that is inherent and ingrained in the Requests library. Primarily, I used it to build pythonpackages.com. In particular, I used it to communicate with the almost-equally-elegant (IMHO) GitHub API. This is why I like requests (among other reasons): I don't need to use a &amp;quot;third party&amp;quot; library to communicate with the GitHub API. Such libraries (I think) attempt to make my job easier by hiding complexity and presenting simpler APIs to use. This is sometimes necessary, but no substitute for &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; simple APIs and good documentation (both of which GitHub and Kenneth provide, with their respective APIs.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What new programming technique did you learn in 2012?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript: check. Unit testing: check. These are techniques I have learned enough of to be effective in my &amp;quot;day job&amp;quot; (I'm self-employed). But I learned (finally) that I am primarily: a Python Web Developer. And it feels good to say that. I use Python, and related web technologies to build web applications for my clients. I typically only care to learn enough of a technology to get my job done, then I lose interest (for the most part). That's because I'm also a Hacker. I identify significantly with this monicker because it fits who I am and how I conduct myself professionally. I care about getting the job done above all else. And if there is a job to be done, my intellectual curiosity knows no bounds. If the job is done, I'm going to play guitar. So whatever the technique, I'll learn it if it's something I care about for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Which open source project did you contribute to the most in 2012 ? What did you do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year that Plone did not consume my every moment. I also spent significant time working on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/buildout"&gt;Buildout&lt;/a&gt; (INI-config-driven system to install Python packages and other software, &amp;amp; perform other related and miscellaneous tasks) and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python-imaging"&gt;Pillow (PIL fork)&lt;/a&gt;. With the help of many others, I hope to get a Python 3.3 compatible release of Pillow out by PyCon 2013. And I'll support Buildout &amp;lt; 2.x until such time as Buildout 2.x goes mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Which Python blog or website did you read the most in 2012?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planets: Django, Mozilla, Plone, Python. Reddits: Python. Other feeds: Hacker News &amp;amp; Tech Crunch. I added Tech Crunch this year to satisfy my &amp;quot;startup itch&amp;quot;, as was recommended to me by Jonathon Perrelli of Fortify.vc in DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. What are the three top things you want to learn in 2013?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to hustle. Hustling, and more hustling. I've gained a lot (enough?) technical skill over the years. Now I want to put that skill to good use in business. I've managed to remain self-employed for a number of years, now I'd like to employ others full time, build successful businesses and otherwise &amp;quot;expand my empire&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. What is the top software, application or library you wish someone would write in 2013?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that I get more significant time to put into my &amp;quot;baby&amp;quot;: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pythonpackages"&gt;pythonpackages.com&lt;/a&gt;. In particular, I'm considering adding a Travis-like service which would spawn Windows VMs to run tests and produce executables for Python packages (to address a particular pain point I've discovered along the way: people want to support Windows, but often don't have the ability to do so easily.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy (Python) New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to do your own list? Here's how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy-paste the questions and answer to them in your blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweet it with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/search/realtime?q=%232012pythonmeme&amp;amp;src=typd"&gt;#2012pythonmeme&lt;/a&gt; hashtag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="Django"></category><category term="Mozilla"></category><category term="Plone"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Hello</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net//2012/10/23/django-hello/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-23T13:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>aclark</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2012-10-23:/2012/10/23/django-hello/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Django doesn't really need a hello world style introduction, its documentation speaks for itself. But this is what &lt;strong&gt;Hello World&lt;/strong&gt; in Django looks like to me. I hate boilerplate and I love reducing software down to its core components; just enough to start the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;setup.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
from setuptools import setup

setup(
    name='hello',
)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;requirements.txt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Django==1.4.1
-e .
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;settings.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
from hello import urls


DEBUG = True
ROOT_URLCONF = urls
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;urls.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
from django.conf.urls import patterns

urlpatterns = patterns(
    '',
    (r'', 'hello.views.index'),
)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;views.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
from django.http import HttpResponse
import datetime


# Based on https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.4/topics/http/views/
def index(request):
    &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
    This function takes a Django request object and returns a 'Hello World'
    style response, by wrapping some HTML in a Django response object.
    &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;

    now = datetime.datetime.now()
    html = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;It is now %s.&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&amp;quot; % now
    return HttpResponse(html)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installation"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ git clone this-repo
$ cd this-repo
$ virtualenv .
$ bin/pip install -r requirements.txt
$ bin/django-admin.py runserver --settings=hello.settings
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The above code can be found here:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/aclark4life/django-hello"&gt;https://github.com/aclark4life/django-hello&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consider a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;"
        src="https://www.gittip.com/aclark4life/widget.html"
        width="48pt" height="20pt"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Django"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello, Django!</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net//2012/10/15/hello-django/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-15T18:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>aclark</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2012-10-15:/2012/10/15/hello-django/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="test-post"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Test post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a test post to create a Django tag feed. Hello, Django planet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Django"></category></entry></feed>