<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Alex Clark</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.aclark.net/feeds/Misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.aclark.net/</id><updated>2012-05-11T09:58:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Adam Yauch has passed</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net/adam-yauch-has-passed.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-11T09:58:00+02:00</updated><author><name>aclark@aclark.net</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2012-05-11:adam-yauch-has-passed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And why it matters to tech people, like me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I hope my tech colleagues will indulge my thoughts on the recent
passing of Beastie Boy Adam Yauch.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: I &amp;lt;3 the Beastie Boys and will miss Adam Yauch; and I suspect
many others in the tech world do, and will, too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-i-came-from"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where I came from&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I've been trying to emulate my heroes. It
started with pop music in the 80s and artists like Michael Jackson,
Madonna, and of course the Beastie Boys. While I was obsessed with
Michael Jackson back then, I don't recall trying too hard to emulate the
Beastie Boys… until the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early 90s, I was just out of high school (where I discovered Led
Zeppelin, Pink Floyd, Beatles, Stones etc), was working full time at
Chili's, and had no serious plans for college. I was really into music,
but didn't have the social skills required to participate in any
meaningful activities, like playing in a band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I loved music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to Nirvana, Beastie Boys, and any number of other pop, rock
and rap acts of the 90s. I went to rock shows at the 8x10 in Baltimore
and 9:30 club in DC. I went to festivals like the HFSistival and
Lollapalooza. Throughout the decade, I formulated my thoughts on how I
would, one day, start a band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say the Beastie Boys were inspirational to me during this time period
would be a colossal understatement (remember the first time you saw the
&amp;quot;So Watcha Want?&amp;quot; video?) While I wholly identified with the
angst-ridden music of Nirvana, I also equally identified with the good
natured spirit of, and dope-ass-jams from, the Beastie Boys: three guys
producing kick ass music with, among other instruments, a &amp;quot;bullshit mic,
made out of plastic&amp;quot;. Most importantly: they never took themselves too
seriously. They made great music, but they were also just like you and
me. They made you feel like you could do it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 90s and early to mid 2000s, I finally got a chance to play
music. I started a band, played some shows, recorded a few albums, and
had a lot of fun. Most importantly: I proved to myself I could do it.
The shows I put on with my band were awesome; they were true rock shows:
those in which the audience responded positively, viscerally. There is
no better feeling in the world than that type of self-expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="image0-who-i-am-now"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="#id1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id2"&gt;`|image0|`_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Who I am now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the band imploded, and I found a new obsession: technology. I
have always been obsessed with tech, but never focused on it exclusively
until the mid to late 2000s. Now I have a new set of heroes to emulate,
and many new things to prove to myself I can do. Maybe I'll even play
music again one day, but if I don't, I know that I accomplished, on some
level, what I set out to do. And that is a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-we-are-all-headed"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where we are all headed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all headed forward, now, without Adam Yauch to inspire us anew.
This sucks more than words can express; but it is, alas, a part of life.
Without death to make life precious, there would be no joy in living. We
all only have a short period of time in life to accomplish our goals, so
it is important that we spend time trying to do so. (And if your goals
include helping other people, bonus points from Adam.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot thank Adam Yauch (MCA), Adam Horovitz (Ad-Rock), and Mike D
enough; for providing me with all the inspiration I needed, when I
needed it, to live my life; it has made all the difference. I know that
Ad-Rock and Mike D will continue to live their lives; and whether that
includes performing as &amp;quot;Beastie Boys&amp;quot; or not, does not matter to me; I
will still be watching, waiting to be inspired again. And to Adam Yauch
who has rapped, joked, snowboarded, and philanthropized his way through
all our lives: thank you for the inspiration; I use it every day, and
I'll never forget it was &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; and your closest two brothers Ad-Rock and
Mike D who gave it to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="system-messages section"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Docutils System Messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/Users/aclark/Developer/blog/content/adam-yauch-has-passed.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 60); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="#id2"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Unknown target name: &amp;quot;|image0|&amp;quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Mozilla"></category><category term="Plone"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>I need something to do</title><link href="http://blog.aclark.net/i-need-something-to-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-22T17:06:00+01:00</updated><author><name>aclark@aclark.net</name></author><id>tag:blog.aclark.net,2010-03-22:i-need-something-to-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I would like to think I have done &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://plone.org/2008"&gt;my&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aclark.net/plone-site-admin"&gt;share&lt;/a&gt; for Plone over the past
few years. In return, I know that Plone has done its share for me. I
have learned a lot, made a good living, and met a lot of amazing folks
who have really inspired me to be the best I can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is time for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_287&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;492&amp;quot;
caption=&amp;quot;Image credit:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://screenmusings.org/ForrestGump/pages/fg_0885.htm"&gt;http://screenmusings.org/ForrestGump/pages/fg_0885.htm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="#id3"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id4"&gt;`|Image
credit:
http://screenmusings.org/ForrestGump/pages/fg\_0885.htm|`_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my life were the movie &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109830/"&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/a&gt;, this would be the part where
Forrest stops running, stands in the highway for a minute… then turns
around and goes home to Greenbow Alabama (which as it turns out is a
fictional town, who knew?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gointosail.wordpress.com/2009/03/19/the-end/"&gt;*(Apparently this person had the same epiphany!)*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a drastic change mind you, just a re-focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, I would like to reach out to the community I know and love
(Plone!) and see if anyone has anything for me to do. Please &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:aclark&amp;#64;aclark.net?subject=&amp;quot;Hire%20Alex%20Clark&amp;quot;"&gt;contact
me&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested, and please tell all your friends too! You
never know who knows who and who is looking for what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a little bit about what I have done professionally and
what I would like to do now, followed by some requirements I hope can be
met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I have done:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I received a &lt;strong&gt;Computer Science degree&lt;/strong&gt; in May 1998 after about 10
years of undergrad education (transferred, changed majors, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've done a lot of &lt;strong&gt;system administration and network engineering&lt;/strong&gt;,
mostly for ISPs including AOLnet (back in the day).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have done a lot of &lt;strong&gt;Plone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started doing Plone at my last full-time system administrator
job, and became so obsessed with it that I had to &lt;strong&gt;quit to
pursue&lt;/strong&gt;it&lt;strong&gt;full time&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly thanks to the support of my
wife Amy, and Paul Boos and Nate Aune who handed me my first
contracts!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have &lt;strong&gt;organized monthly meetings&lt;/strong&gt;for ZPUGDC for the last 4
years or so, taking over for Joel Burton when he moved to
California. We are now in the process of becoming a 501c3 so we
can expand our focus and serve the community in bigger and better
ways. ZPUGDC is not a full time job, but it as a passion (to be a
resource for all things Python in DC).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have owned and operated&lt;strong&gt;ACLARK.NET, LLC&lt;/strong&gt;for the past six
years. All in all this has been an amazing experience and I have
no plans to stop. We are now at the point where we can compete
with all the &amp;quot;big firms&amp;quot; and we intend to do so. But I need time
to answer some RFQs…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;organized&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://plone.org/2008"&gt;Plone Conference 2008&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aclark.net/plone-site-admin"&gt;wrote a book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;upgraded plone.org to Plone 3&lt;/strong&gt;, and now lead the plone.org
&lt;strong&gt;infrastructure team member&lt;/strong&gt;, taking over for Wichert Akkerman
(more or less) when he left. This is something I particularly
enjoy. No wait, I hate it. Just kidding. It is something I like,
and plan to focus on it more in the future to make sure it gets
done right. It is very frustrating to want to do something but not
have&amp;nbsp; time to do it. I'm sure all you Plone consultants know what
I mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have done some &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; programming and evangelism:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have paid particular attention to making ZPUGDC &lt;strong&gt;more
Python-centric&lt;/strong&gt;, by welcoming all Python programmers in the area
not just Plonistas. This has worked out very well and our monthly
attendance has gone from 5-6 to 15-20. Each month, we go around
the room and talk about &amp;quot;what we are doing with Python&amp;quot;. It is
&lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I write code&lt;/strong&gt;. I am particularly proud that working for myself
has afforded me my first paid programming job (programming for
system administration doesn't really count IMO). There is a ton to
learn: Networking frameworks like Twisted, Web application
frameworks like Zope, Django, Turbo Gears, Pylons, BFG, etc.
Continuous integration with Hudson (OK, that is Java but you can
use it on your Python code ;-)), Documentation with Sphinx. And so
on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I would like to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source Software&lt;/strong&gt;: I really like open source software. It
started in the mid 1990s when I realized that there was this thing
called the Internet and that people had been writing code for years
and making it available for general use to anyone interested. That
just floored me. I can still remember the thrill of borrowing a UNIX
text book from my professor the summer before I started CS classes.
At the time, it seemed like UNIX and open source walked hand in hand
and I became obsessed with both. I realize now there is much more to
that story, but that is how the seeds were planted. Anyway, open
source is for me and I am for open source. I am not sure what that
means in terms of job opportunities, but maybe I could be an
evangelist like Mark Hinkle, and evangelize Your Software like he
evangelizes Zenoss. Just a thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plone, Python, Zope, Zenoss&lt;/strong&gt;: I really like these open source
projects, in particular. Any paid position that involves almost any
aspect of these projects would make me happy. I have pimped myself
out to Zenoss and I eventually expect to hang out my Zenoss shingle
and start doing add-ons, customizations, etc. for Zenoss users. But I
am not quite there yet. I know Plone, and can handle most development
and deployment tasks. I am particularly interested in large-scale
deployments (e.g. City of Austin type clients, only with a better
outcome ;-)).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Busy work&lt;/strong&gt;. It sounds silly, but repetitive tasks fit my brain.
Automating large scale deployments. Configuration management. System
updates. These things I can do, and help you with too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn&lt;/strong&gt;: If there is one thing I've learned after learning so much
over the years, it is that I hardly know anything. I hope to be a
part of team that offers a significant growth opportunity. It's time
to raise the bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I require to work for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six month contract or longer&lt;/strong&gt;. Whatever I sign on to do, it has to
last six months or more (preferably until the end of 2010). This is
the time frame I am particularly concerned about (for a variety of
personal reasons). I can start April 1 or after. Repeat: it is
definitely OK if it lasts longer than six months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel&lt;/strong&gt;. I can travel almost anywhere in the world, as long as you
pay for it ;-). But seriously, working from home is a requirement,
but meetings (monthly? bi-monthly?) in your city should not be a
problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun and flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;. I do Plone for a living because Plone is
fun. I work very hard to make sure your needs are met, and I ask for
a lot of flexibility in return. Deadlines are not a problem, but the
ability to act independently to meet the deadline is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paid Plone work&lt;/strong&gt;. Ideally someone will hire me to do all the
things I already love to do like maintaining plone.org, sprinting on
various tasks, perhaps joining the Plone 4.1 Framework Team. Anything
and everything I can do to make the Plone project better and
stronger. This of course does not have to be the main focus of the
work, but it would be nice if some time could be allocated officially
towards these tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part time&lt;/strong&gt;. Ideally I'd like to put in about 20 hours per week on
some project, and spend the other 20 hours on ACLARK.NET, ZPUGDC,
INC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all, I am flexible. This post is about me, but I am certainly
willing to listen to what you, prospective employer, has to offer. If
there is a good fit, I am confident we can make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I almost forgot, my updated resume is here:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aclark.net/team/aclark/resume"&gt;http://aclark.net/team/aclark/resume&lt;/a&gt;. Or if you prefer PDF:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aclark.net/team/aclark/resume-pdf"&gt;http://aclark.net/team/aclark/resume-pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- |Image credit: --&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: WARNING/2 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/Users/aclark/Developer/blog/content/i-need-something-to-do.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 172)&lt;/p&gt;
malformed substitution definition.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: WARNING/2 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/Users/aclark/Developer/blog/content/i-need-something-to-do.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 173)&lt;/p&gt;
Explicit markup ends without a blank line; unexpected unindent.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://screenmusings.org/ForrestGump/pages/fg_0885"&gt;http://screenmusings.org/ForrestGump/pages/fg_0885&lt;/a&gt;.htm| image:: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.aclark.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fg_0885.jpg"&gt;http://blog.aclark.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fg_0885.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
.. &lt;a href="#id1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id2"&gt;|image1|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; image:: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.aclark.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fg_0885.jpg"&gt;http://blog.aclark.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/fg_0885.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-messages section"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Docutils System Messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/Users/aclark/Developer/blog/content/i-need-something-to-do.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 173); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="#id2"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Undefined substitution referenced: &amp;quot;image1&amp;quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id3"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/Users/aclark/Developer/blog/content/i-need-something-to-do.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 14); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="#id4"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Unknown target name: &amp;quot;|image credit: http://screenmusings.org/forrestgump/pages/fg_0885.htm|&amp;quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Plone"></category></entry></feed>